<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Sam Machin</title>
    <link>https://sammachin.com/categories/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Sam Machin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 11:58:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sammachin.com/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Echo Show Security Camera with a Pi</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/build-your-own-rasp-pi-security-camera-for-the-echo-show/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 11:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/build-your-own-rasp-pi-security-camera-for-the-echo-show/</guid>
      <description>The Echo Show is the first Alexa enabled device from Amazon with a screen, with this device Amazon introduced some new capabilities within the Sklls SDK particularly around video, one of these is the ability to view home security cameras such as the Nest and the Ring Doorbell using the command &amp;ldquo;Alexa show X camera&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AlexaPi - Its come a long way</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/alexapi-its-come-a-long-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 22:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/alexapi-its-come-a-long-way/</guid>
      <description>Its over a year now since I released the first version of my AlexaPi code that turned a Raspberry Pi into your own Amazon Echo like device via the Alexa Voice Service API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train Ticket Machines - What about the Power Users</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/train-ticket-machines-what-about-the-power-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 14:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/train-ticket-machines-what-about-the-power-users/</guid>
      <description>Plenty of articles have been written on the UX of train ticket machines, while they tend to vary by train operating company they&amp;rsquo;re usually one of 2-3 varients and usually generally awful to use!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Story of Enterprise IT:</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/a-story-of-enterprise-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 11:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/a-story-of-enterprise-it/</guid>
      <description>Spock: Captain, Klingon Bird of Prey de-cloaking off the port side Kirk: Mr Sulu, ready photon torpedos Sulu: Captain, there&amp;rsquo;s a problem, Kirk: What Mr Sulu?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Apple Sim - Its a Bad thing</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/the-apple-sim-its-a-bad-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 09:52:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/the-apple-sim-its-a-bad-thing/</guid>
      <description>Lots of people are getting excited about one of the features of the new iPad Air 2 - The Apple Sim, its being pitched as a single sim card that allows you to switch carriers as you please, I suspect that under the hood its a special kind of multi profile sim card that actually contains profiles for each carrier, or possibly even allows new profiles to be loaded over the air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A platform based bank account</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/a-platform-based-bank-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 10:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/a-platform-based-bank-account/</guid>
      <description>For a long time I&amp;rsquo;ve always felt that telecoms and banking/payments are pretty similar industries when it comes to technology, both handle massive amounts of real time transactional data, making a payment in a shop using a visa card is fairly similar to the idea of sending someone an SMS when you strip it back, of course payments have to have higher levels of security than telecoms but we&amp;rsquo;re in the same ballpark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A &#39;real&#39; utility</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/a-real-utility/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 07:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/a-real-utility/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday evening I noticed some problems with our mains supply at home, the lights were dimming for a short period of time maybe 2-3 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three InTouch</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/three-intouch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 15:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/three-intouch/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been lucky enough over the past few weeks to trial Three&amp;rsquo;s InTouch app, which allows you to make and receive calls and SMS on your phone over WiFi, ideal for times when you don&amp;rsquo;t have coverage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New site Old Blog posts</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/new-site-old-blog-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 16:14:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/new-site-old-blog-posts/</guid>
      <description>I finally decided I needed to overhaul my &amp;lsquo;site&amp;rsquo; I had a very ageing wordpress blog that hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen much of an update in several years and really just needed taking out an shooting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Payments &amp; Graceful Degradation</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/electronic-payments-graceful-degradation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 17:03:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/electronic-payments-graceful-degradation/</guid>
      <description>Theres a lot of hype around NFC &amp;amp; mobile payments going around, analyst are predicting it as the next big thing and rumour mills are churning out stories about the iPhone 5 having NFC faster than a Foxconn plant on double time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android, Buyer Currency Support C-</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/android-buyer-currency-support-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 10:56:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/android-buyer-currency-support-c/</guid>
      <description>One of the new features announced by Google yesterday was support for &amp;ldquo;Buyer Currency&amp;rdquo; now this may come as something of a shock to iPhone users but chargeable apps in the Android Market have been billed in the developers currency since launch!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Breakfast</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/my-breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 11:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/my-breakfast/</guid>
      <description>Last week I went to DroidCon in London, as I had an early start and I got the venue with half an hour to spare I had breakfast at the Breakfast Club Cafe in Angel, unfortunately our expense system only allows 50 characters in the description field when claiming expenses which I hardly think does this experience justice (nor can I claim to be embracing the spirit of Sarbanes-Oxley) therefore I&amp;rsquo;m writing a post which I can shorten with bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That syncing feeling</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/that-syncing-feeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2009 20:44:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/that-syncing-feeling/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s been some recent discussions around contact syncing and particularly issues wiht the HTC Hero&amp;rsquo;s latest update.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T-Mobile UK Capped Data Charge - Hidden Rip Off</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/t-mobile-uk-caped-data-charge-hidden-rip-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 19:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/t-mobile-uk-caped-data-charge-hidden-rip-off/</guid>
      <description>I recently managed to get my wife to become a regular user of mobile data, great I thought this stuff is finally getting mainstream traction, Until we got this months bill&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenMIC - Mobile Data Charging</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/openmic-mobile-data-charging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2009 21:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/openmic-mobile-data-charging/</guid>
      <description>We had a very interesting discussion at OpenMIC 2 today, I put the topic up as &amp;ldquo;Lets Design the Perfect Mobile Data Charging Model&amp;rdquo; quite a daunting task but I thought it might attract attention</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 3.0 MMS Settings</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/iphone-30-mms-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 15:31:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/iphone-30-mms-settings/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with my unlocked 3.0 iPhone 3G for a week or so now and I&amp;rsquo;ve just got the MMS Settings sorted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T-Mobile G1 vs. iPhone - Round One to iPhone</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/t-mobile-g1-vs-iphone-round-one-to-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 23:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/t-mobile-g1-vs-iphone-round-one-to-iphone/</guid>
      <description>So the G1 is out, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a chance to play with one in a T-Mobile store and it seems like a nice OS, however it doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like an iPhone killer yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Broadband signals the Death of WiFi Hotspots</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/mobile-broadband-signals-the-death-of-wifi-hotspots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2008 15:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/mobile-broadband-signals-the-death-of-wifi-hotspots/</guid>
      <description>Its been a long time since I last wrote a proper post and I doubt this will be that, however having just spent the afternoon chatting with the guys at carsonifiedabout whats happening in the mobile industry I’m feeling all inspired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2008 Predictions in Mobile</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/2008-predictions-in-mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2008 19:32:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/2008-predictions-in-mobile/</guid>
      <description>Better late than never, Ive put down some of my thoughts as to what _might_happen in the mobile industry in 2008.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Web 2.0 Life</title>
      <link>https://sammachin.com/blog/my-web-20-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2007 20:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sammachin.com/blog/my-web-20-life/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been thinking about my whole web2.0 life for a few weeks now and the multitude of different platforms out there.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>